(老鼠)
(Mouse)
(这部剧纯属虚构，与……无关)
(This drama is purely fictional and is not associated with...)
(实际的人、组织、地点或事件。)
(actual people, organizations, locations, or incidents.)
(拍摄符合COVID-19指南…)
(Filming was in compliance with COVID-19 guidelines...)
(并为儿童演员提供咨询服务。)
(and counseling was provided for child actors.)
(包括动物在内的大部分场景都使用了CGI。)
(CGI was used in most scenes that include animals.)
有时，我会随机去打猎。
At times, I go on random hunting trips.
这位老太太看到了一些她不该看到的东西……
This old lady saw something she shouldn't have...
最终成为了一个意外的目标。
and ended up as an unexpected target.
直到它咽下最后一口气
Until it takes its last breath,
猎物应该为宝贵的生命而战。
a prey should fight for dear life.
然而，这种特定的猎物缺乏这样做的能量。
However, this certain prey lacks the energy to do so.
所以这次追捕太容易了
Which is what makes this hunt too easy...
和无聊。
and boring.
(我的第一名被别人抢走了。)
(I lost top of the class to someone else.)
为什么我不能…
Why couldn't I...
生来如此吗?
have been born this way?
所有的好。
All good.
我…
I...
希望能像他一样。
wish to be like him.
我希望成为他。
I wish to be him.
(郑在勋，郑巴莲)
(Jung Jae Hoon, Jung Ba Reum)
(老鼠)
(Mouse)
我们……
We're...
实验室里的小白鼠。
lab mice.
Lab mice.
我们是……
We are...
实验室里的小白鼠。
lab mice.
如果不是Sung Yo Han
If it wasn't Sung Yo Han,
(凶手Sung Yo Han住在这里。)
(Sung Yo Han, the murderer, lives here.)
谁杀了我祖母?
who killed my grandmother?
(集18)
(Episode 18)
我留下了詹妮弗的照片。
I left behind the photo of Jennifer.
容巴留姆去找它，
Jung Ba Reum went to find it,
但如果他们先拿到呢?
but what if they get to it first?
不，我们再等一会儿。
No, we'll wait a while longer.
只是一个第二。
Just a second.
真讨厌。
Darn it.
那照片呢?你找到了吗?
What about the photo? Did you find it?
为什么?这是一张照片吗?
Why? Is it a photo...
不应该被某些人看到吗?
that shouldn't be seen by certain people?
什么?
What?
有一天，我收到一个匿名者的短信。
This one day, I received a text from an anonymous sender.
——一个文本?——我的妈妈,
- A text? - My mom,
在民，还有我的继父。
Jae Min, and my stepfather.
在我决定为我的家人报仇之后，
After I made the decision to avenge my family,
我日夜寻找他。
I searched for him day and night.
他不是有前科吗?
Is he not an ex-con?
他看起来像是会出拳的人。
He looked like someone who knew how to punch.
(宋秀浩，一拳二拳)
(Song Soo Ho, One-Two Boxing)
(北京区石津洞6-50号，武镇)
(6-50 Seokjin-dong, Bukyeong-gu, Moojin)
(Mugwan拳击俱乐部)
(Mugwan Boxing Club)
我们关闭。
We're closed.
我立刻认出了他。
I immediately recognized him.
就在那一天……
That's the day when...
我内心被压抑的杀手释放了出来。
the suppressed killer within me let loose.
在我的大脑植入手术之后，
Following my brain implant surgery,
我的那一面因为宋友韩而沉睡，
that side of me laid dormant thanks to Sung Yo Han,
但一件事把它推了回去。
but an incident pushed it back out.
模仿我之前的杀人手法。
The killings that mimicked my previous ones.
胡亨哲不是一个模仿者。
Woo Hyung Chul wasn't a copycat.
在他犯下谋杀之后
After he committed the murders,
有人留下了假胸针，假项链，
someone left a fake brooch, a necklace,
甚至还有薄荷的味道……
and even the scent of mint...
我作证说闻到了现场的气味
that I testified to smelling at the scene.
我最后杀了吴亨哲…
I ended up killing Woo Hyung Chul...
我内心的杀手再次苏醒。
and the killer within me awoke once more.
会是谁呢?
Who could it have been?
为什么有人把宋秀镐的位置发给了我?
Why was Song Soo Ho's location texted to me?
究竟为什么?
Why on earth?
为什么要上演胡亨哲的犯罪场景?
Why were the scenes of Woo Hyung Chul's crimes staged?
我不知道。
I don't know.
触发我。
To trigger me.
唤醒我内心的杀手。
To awake the killer within me.
我得到了一个猎物。
I was given a prey to hunt.
他们这样做的目的是什么?
What could be their goal in doing such a thing?
他们从一开始就知道我出生了……
They were aware from the start that I was born...
带有精神病基因。
with the psychopathic gene.
我记得宋友韩临死前对我说的话。
I remembered what Sung Yo Han said to me before dying.
据他说，我们只是小白鼠。
According to him, we were lab mice.
你必须参与进来，让他们知道…
You have to be involved for them to know...
我们都有这种基因。
that we both had the gene.
我…我不知道你在说什么。
I... I have no idea what you're talking about.
你不?
You don't?
那为什么我的日记…
Then why is my diary...
还有宋友韩用来联系你的一次性手机
and Sung Yo Han's burner phone he used to contact you...
在你的行李里吗?
over there in your belongings?
用我能理解的方式解释一下。
Explain to me in a way that I'd understand.
你从一开始就知道我是捕食者。
You knew from the start that I was the Predator.
是的,我知道。
Yes, I knew.
当我第一次听说韩国的连环谋杀案时…
When I first heard of the serial murders in Korea...
可能是精神变态犯的
possibly committed by a psychopath,
我以为凶手可能是两个男孩中的一个。
I thought the killer could be 1 of the 2 boys.
激动之下，我直接来到了韩国。
Agitated, I came straight to Korea.
当时,
Back then,
我以为你杀了你的家人。
I thought you had murdered your family.
所以我才确定你就是捕食者。
That's why I was sure you were the Predator.
我去看了另一个男孩，以防万一。
I went to see the other boy just in case though.
你应该好好照顾自己，知道吗。
You should take better care of yourself, you know.
在他的眼里，我看到了明显的嫉妒。
In his eyes, I saw obvious jealousy.
你在真正的捕食者身上看不到的那种。
The kind you never see in a true predator.
那时我才知道……
That's when I knew...
Sung Yo Han是无辜的。
Sung Yo Han was innocent.
我试图阻止你杀人。
I tried to stop you from killing.
你偏离轨道了。
You were going off the rails.
经过再三考虑，我联系了宋佑翰。
After much consideration, I contacted Sung Yo Han.
李医生!
Dr. Lee!
不…没有医院。
No... No hospitals.
他们……他们会残忍地杀了我。
They're... They're going to brutally kill me.
谁……谁?
Who... Who?
首先，你得除掉他。
First, you need to get rid of him.
谁……他是谁?
Who... Who is he?
他为什么要这样对你?
Why did he do this to you?
你……你需要…
You... You need...
你得仔细听我说，韩友。
You need to listen to me carefully, Yo Han.
那天，我把一切都告诉了他。
That day, I told him everything.
这就是他帮我的原因。
That's why he helped me.
我有治疗……
I got treated...
在他的地下室。
in his basement.
然后他带我去了废弃的医院。
Then he took me to the abandoned hospital.
你欺骗我，利用我。
You lied to me and used me.
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
我…我试图阻止他们。
I... I tried to stop them.
你为什么不阻止他?
Why aren't you stopping him?
我们说好一旦他表现出杀人的本能就公开。
We agreed to go public once he showed his murder instincts.
我们同意重新提出议事日程。
We agreed to reintroduce the agenda.
(你为什么不遵守诺言?)
Why aren't you keeping your promise?
已经死了好多人了!
So many people have died already!
你怎么能眼睁睁看着他们死去?
How could you just watch them die?
你疯了。你不能再这样下去了。
You're crazy. You need to stop this now.
他现在失控了。
He's out of control right now.
你以为我会袖手旁观什么都不做吗?
Do you think I'll just sit back and do nothing?
这背后是谁?
Who's behind this?
告诉我是谁!告诉我!
Tell me who it is! Tell me!
是谁?谁是混蛋?
Who is it? Who's the jerk?
崔小姐，什么风把你吹来了?
Ms. Choi, what brings you here?
我想请你帮个忙
I had a favor to ask,
但我想如果我在电话里问你，你可能会拒绝。
but I thought you might refuse if I asked you over the phone.
我有个客人，我们能下次再谈吗?
I have a guest over, so can we talk next time?
不会太久的。
It won't take long.
你能做个采访吗，荣格警官?
Can you do an interview, Officer Jung?
什么面试?
What interview?
莫津连环谋杀案?
The Moojin serial murder case?
是的。你是唯一的幸存者。
Yes. You're the only survivor.
所以我真的很想让你做个采访…
So I really want you to do an interview...
那天发生的事。
about what happened that day.
我很快就会告诉你一切。
I'll soon tell you everything.
但不是现在。
But not now.
什么?
What?
——你好吗?——荣格。
- Hello? - Officer Jung.
你怎么这么久才接电话?
What took you so long to answer your phone?
谢天谢地他在打电话。
Thank goodness he was on the phone.
你可以来我家。
You can come to my place.
我去看看你能住在哪。
I'll look into where you can stay.
我要找到詹妮弗的照片。
I need to find Jennifer's photo.
我马上去拿。
I'll go get it soon.
我现在就要。
I need it now.
如果那些人拿到了那张照片，
If those guys get their hands on that photo,
他们就会发现我还活着。
they'll find out I'm still alive.
-好的，我现在就过去。- - -…
- Okay, I'll drop by right now. - And...
有件事你得知道。
there's something you need to know.
那是什么?
What's that?
别担心。警察会保护你的。
Don't worry. The police will protect you.
警察吗?
The police?
Yu Na……
Yu Na...
我一提到"警察"就停止了谈话。
stopped talking the moment I mentioned "police".
-无法联系到接收者…-为什么柯警探…
- The receiver cannot be reached... - Why isn't Detective Ko...
回答他的电话吗?
answering his phone?
(我们承诺保护我们公民的安全。)
(We promise to keep our citizens safe.)
柯警探，听说你找到那辆车了。
Detective Ko, I heard you tracked down the car.
你的朋克。
You punk.
柯警探，你在干什么?
Detective Ko, what are you doing?
你是个变态，对吧?
You're a psychopath, aren't you?
——侦探Ko。-放开我!下车!
- Detective Ko. - Let go of me! Get off!
英航Reum !侦探柯!
Ba Reum! Detective Ko!
-你为什么要这么做?——移动!
- Why are you doing this? - Move!
你杀了人……
You killed everyone...
跟我来。
Follow me.
侦探柯!
Detective Ko!
-柯警探，住手!- Bong易。
- Detective Ko, stop it! - Bong Yi.
我的天啊。
My gosh.
- Bong易!Bong易!-邦伊，别说了。
- Bong Yi! Bong Yi! - Bong Yi, stop.
放开他。
Let go of him.
-怎么了?-柯警探，怎么了?
- What's the matter? - Detective Ko, what's going on?
-你在干什么?-放开我!
- What do you think you're doing? - Get off me!
离开我!让我走!
Get off me! Let me go!
你应该去。
You should go.
不,等等!
No, wait!
- Ba Reum !侦探柯!——你。
- Ba Reum! Detective Ko! - You.
——嘿!——你的朋克。
- Hey! - You punk.
你杀了所有人，不是吗?
You killed everyone, didn't you?
姜德洙，李在植，金秉泰。
Kang Duk Soo, Lee Jae Shik, and Kim Byung Tae.
你为什么不否认?
Why aren't you denying it?
你真的杀了他们吗?
Did you really kill them?
-嘿，你在说什么?-他杀了他们。
- Hey, what are you talking about? - He killed them all.
我有证据。
I have proof.
李侦探在哪儿?
Where's Detective Lee?
李敏秀在哪里?
Where's Lee Min Soo?
(莫津布布派出所)
(Moojin Bukbu Police Station)
敏秀!
Min Soo!
嘿，你在里面，不是吗?
Hey, you're in there, aren't you?
快出来!
Get out of there!
外面来了!
Come outside now!
-天啊，这次你想要什么?——你的朋克!
- Gosh, what do you want this time? - You punk!
-在哪里?在哪里?——是什么?
- Where is it? Where is it? - Where's what?
先生,冷静下来。先生!
Sir, calm down. Sir!
他是怎么发现的?
How did he find out?
他有什么证据?
What kind of evidence does he have?
现在不是时候
Now isn't the right time
我得争取时间，直到找到杀害奇果的凶手。
I need to buy time until I find out who killed Chi Kook.
我现在得否认。
I need to deny it for now.
只是一个第二。
Just a second.
——停止它。-放开我。
- Stop it. - Get off me.
天哪,阻止它。
Gosh, stop it.
下车。
Get off.
——先生!-走开，你这个废物!
- Sir! - Move, you punk!
你们俩是什么?
What are you two?
你们是在合作吗?
Are you two working as a team?
他清理现场的时候你负责杀人吗?
Are you in charge of the killing while he cleans up the scene?
你说我帮他收拾是什么意思?
What do you mean I cleaned up after him?
"清理现场"?
"Cleans up the scene"?
车载摄像头录下了6264号车的录像，和上演的自杀。
The dash cam video of the car 6264, with the staged suicide.
你从我这里偷走了，然后冲掉了!
You stole it from me and flushed it!
他被杀了吗?
He got killed?
-别装作你不知道!——先生,请。
- Don't act like you don't know! - Sir, please.
你为什么一直这样对我?
Why do you keep doing this to me?
你看到我把它扔了吗?
Did you see me throw it away?
-他好像什么都不知道。——告诉我。
- He doesn't seem to know anything. - Tell me.
你看到我把录像处理掉了吗?
Did you see me get rid of the footage?
那你在浴室里做什么?
Then what were you doing in the bathroom?
-我拉屎冲厕所了-他是…
- I took a dump and flushed. - Is he a member...
-有问题吗?-组织的?
- Got a problem? - of the organization?
-你们这些混球!——先生,请。
- You darn punks! - Sir, please.
木奇，够了。
Moo Chi, that's enough.
——这些朋克…-我说够了!
- These punks... - I said that's enough!
带他们去审讯室。
Take them to the interrogation room.
-是长官-是长官
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
真讨厌!
Darn it!
很好。好的,很好。
Fine. Okay, fine.
让我们好好调查一下。
Let's properly investigate them.
去审讯室。走了。
Go to the interrogation room. Get going.
警探，你能让我走吗?
Detective, can you please let me go?
侦探心!侦探心!
Detective Shin! Detective Shin!
请放我出去。
Please let me out.
冷静下来。让我看看你的手。
Calm down. Let me see your hand.
-我的手没事。-看起来你受伤了。
- My hand's fine. - It looks like you got hurt.
小心。
Careful.
如果你把它弄成这样，会留下疤痕的。
If you leave it like this, it'll leave a scar.
这是怎么呢
What's going on?
-我不知道-柯警探为什么…
- I have no idea. - Why is Detective Ko...
对巴留姆这么生气?
so angry at Ba Reum?
等它干了就戴上。
Put this on once it dries.
以后再用一些。
Apply some more of this later too.
稍等片刻。我们很快就会让你自由。
Just wait a little bit. We'll let you free soon.
侦探心!
Detective Shin!
申探长，为什么柯探长认为…
Detective Shin, why does Detective Ko think...
荣格警官杀了人?
Officer Jung killed someone?
保持安静。停止说话无稽之谈。
Be quiet. Stop talking nonsense.
他是怎么发现的?
How did he find out?
不能让他知道是巴留姆干的。
He can't find out that it was Ba Reum.
冷静点，告诉我你在说什么。
Calm down and tell me what you're talking about.
Ba Reum，那个朋克…
Ba Reum, that punk...
我不知道你在说什么。
I don't know what you're talking about.
我查了行车记录仪的录像。
I checked the dashcam footage.
但李警探从我这里拿走了在混乱中把它处理掉了。
But Detective Lee took it from me and got rid of it amid the chaos.
他把它冲进了厕所
He flushed it down the toilet.
我们得马上找!
We need to look for it now!
天啊，我都快疯了。
My gosh, this is driving me crazy.
我在浴室拉完屎出来，
I was coming out after taking a dump in the bathroom,
但他突然抓住我的衣领，骂我。
but he suddenly grabbed me by my collar and cussed at me.
我亲眼看到了巴勒姆。
I saw Ba Reum with my own two eyes.
他就在姜德洙被杀的现场。
He was at the scene of Kang Duk Soo's murder scene.
我的猫生了一只小猫……
My cat gave birth to a kitten...
姜德洙死的那天
on the day Kang Duk Soo died.
我在家里陪我表弟。
I was home spending time with my cousin.
李警探故意花时间交了份供词。
Detective Lee purposely took time to hand in the statement...
这是姜德洙的母亲写的。
that Kang Duk Soo's mother wrote.
我之所以迟交是因为我忘了。
I only handed that in late because I forgot.
这是难以置信的。
This is unbelievable.
那些人有同样的纹身。
Those guys have the same tattoos.
-他甚至把它处理掉了。-那是个纹身…
- He even got rid of that. - It was a tattoo...
我前女友名字的首字母
of my ex-girlfriend's initials.
我告诉他我把它扔了，因为我们分手了。
I told him I got rid of it because we broke up.
你在哪里纹的纹身?
Where did you get the tattoo?
他只染了指甲花。但有一天，他要求纹身。
He only got hennas. But one day, he asked for a tattoo.
一个纹身吗?什么样的纹身?
A tattoo? What kind of tattoo?
我们为客户拍照……
We take photos for our customers...
-只要他们有纹身。——好的。
- whenever they get a tattoo. - Okay.
-我会找的。-好吧，帮我个忙。
- I'll look for it. - Okay, please do me a favor.
在这儿。
Here it is.
谢谢你！祝你过得愉快。
Thank you. Have a nice day.
他是和他女朋友一起吃的，是OJ，不是OZ。
He got it with his girlfriend, and it was OJ, not OZ.
我知道它。说真的,朋克。
I knew it. Seriously, that punk.
嗨。
Hi.
什么?
What?
好吧。明白了。
Okay. Got it.
你妻子又失踪了吗?
Did your wife go missing again?
可怜的家伙。
Poor guy.
这是多少次了?
How many times is this?
——这是不同的吗?——这是正确的。
- It's different? - That's right.
他肯定贿赂了纹身店的老板。
He must've bribed the tattoo shop owner.
他没有时间。康警探拿到了地址…
He had no time. Detective Kang got the address...
申警探马上就走了。
and Detective Shin went right away.
不管怎样,回家了。
Anyway, go home.
去哪里?
Go where?
照我说的做，好吗?
Do as I say, will you?
社交媒体上到处都是你殴打容警官的视频。
Videos of you beating Officer Jung is all over social media.
你非得在平民和记者面前这么做吗?
Did you have to do that in front of civilians and reporters?
嘿。你忘记了吗?荣格军官是国子。
Hey. Did you forget? Officer Jung is the National Son.
你成了那个痛打那个可怜孩子的叛徒。
You became the National Traitor who beat up the poor kid.
不管是不是叛徒，我都不在乎。
Traitor or not, I don't care.
“国家的儿子”?整个国家都将陷入极度震惊之中。
"National Son"? The entire nation will be in utter shock.
你应该关心。我们刚接到上级打来的电话…
You should care. We just got a call from above...
暂停你的。
to suspend you.
你现在要去哪里?
Where are you going now?
去经历垃圾场!
To go through dump!
我会找到那张记忆卡的。
I'll find that memory card.
李敏秀也和奥兹在一起?
Lee Min Soo is with OZ too?
车载摄像头录下了6264号车的录像，和上演的自杀。
The dash cam video of the car 6264, with the staged suicide.
它钓了多少鱼?
How much did it catch?
荣格警官，回家休息吧。
Officer Jung, go home and rest.
原谅我。李警探呢?
Excuse me. What about Detective Lee?
我也把他送回家了。
I just sent him home too.
(请登入警务处数据库)
(Please log into the Police Department Database)
(姓名:李敏秀地址:莫津书谷)
(Name: Lee Min Soo Address: Book-gu, Moojin City)
Ki Hyuk，放她走。
Ki Hyuk, let her go.
不管原因是什么，你不能袭击警官。
Whatever the reason may be, you can't assault an officer.
英航Reum在哪?
Where's Ba Reum?
我马上回来。
I'll be right back.
我将这样做。
I'll do it.
不，我去拿。
No, I'll get it.
就算我被抓了，我们也得有一个人活着。
One of us must stay alive even if I get caught.
那个人一定是你。你必须完成这一切。
That person must be you. You need to finish this.
我该怎么办?
What do I do?
韩哟……
Yo Han...
我可怜的Yo Han…
My poor Yo Han...
它去哪儿了?
Where did it go?
你还活着，丹尼尔·李医生。
So you're alive, Dr. Daniel Lee.
嘿!
Hey!
发生了什么事?
What happened?
我去了肉类区一分钟然后…
I went to the meat section for just a minute and...
她也留下了她的毛衣。
She left her sweater too.
(爆炸Yoo华)
(Bang Yoo Hwa)
谢谢你的辛勤工作。你介意我看一下吗?
Thank you for your hard work. Do you mind if I take a look?
——她离开。——什么?
- She left. - What?
请稍等。
Please hang on.
很快就是登陆日了。
It'll be d-day soon.
-荣格警官在哪里?——你臭。
- Where's Officer Jung? - You stink.
你真的挖了大便吗?
Did you really dig in the poop?
你找到了吗?
Did you find it?
太小了。
It's too small.
你臭。去洗洗。出去。
You stink. Go and wash up. Get out.
英航Reum在哪?
Where's Ba Reum?
我让他回家了!
I sent him home!
为什么?如果他毁了证据怎么办?
Why? What if he destroys evidence?
-敏秀呢?-他发邮件要求休假。
- What about Min Soo? - He emailed a vacation request.
——一个假期?-别靠近!你的气味。
- A vacation? - Don't come closer! You smell.
看到了吗?他脱下!
See? He took off!
闵秀说他不会就这么拿走。他说他要告你!
Min Soo says he won't just take it. He says he'll sue you!
气怪人的杀手。
Chi Kook's killer.
李侦探。
Detective Lee.
你的问题是什么?
What's your problem?
你为什么在里面?
Why were you in there?
你们俩不是约在这里见面吗?
Were you two supposed to meet here?
我因为殴打国民之子而被停赛。
I was suspended for beating up the National Son.
给我一个直接的回答。
Give me a straight answer.
否则，我就敲碎你的脑袋，然后进监狱。
Otherwise, I'll crack your skull and go to jail.
你知道我的愿望是什么。
You know what my wish is.
你也杀了奉仪的奶奶，对吧?
You killed Bong Yi's grandma too, didn't you?
因为只有你，警监和我
The reason you, captain, and I were the only ones...
进入物证室的录音是因为你是凶手，
recorded entering the evidence room was because you were the killer,
不是因为凶手避开了摄像头。
not because the killer avoided the camera somehow.
你拿了奉仪给我的钱让我杀了他。
You took the money Bong Yi gave me to kill him.
只有你和申警探知道账单背后的故事。
Only you and Detective Shin know the story behind that bill.
你把它。要杀他。对吧?
You took it. To kill him. Right?
现在一切都说得通了。
Everything makes sense now.
回答我,混蛋。
Answer me, jerk.
你是对的。
You're right.
我杀了他。
I killed him.
什么?
What?
我拿起奶奶的小刀……
I took Granny's knife...
把它放回去……
and put it back...
也
as well.
邦依有危险。
Bong Yi was in danger.
我以为他要杀了她，
I thought he was going to kill her,
所以我先杀了他
so I killed him first.
邦伊知道吗?
Does Bong Yi know?
所以我们分手了。
That's why we broke up.
她说她不介意
She says she's fine with it,
但我无法忍受那种负罪感。
but I couldn't bear the guilt.
但是关于李在植和金秉泰，
But regarding Lee Jae Shik and Kim Byung Tae,
我不知道你看到了什么，但是…
I don't know what you saw, but...
告诉我。
Tell me.
你为什么在李在植被释放那天去监狱?
Why did you go to the prison the day Lee Jae Shik was released?
我肯定被那里的摄像头拍到了。
I must've been caught on camera there.
我接到了崔女士的电话。
I got a call from Ms. Choi.
-从Hong Ju?——是的。
- From Hong Ju? - Yes.
她要董古的电话号码。
She asked for Dong Koo's number.
她说她认为李在植是凶手。
She said she thought Lee Jae Shik was the murderer.
她说想核实一下，我就告诉她了。
She said she wanted to check, so I told her.
但如果这是真的，说明他很危险。
But if that's true, it meant he was dangerous.
这就是我去的原因。因为我很担心。
That's why I went. Because I was worried.
那金秉泰呢?
What about Kim Byung Tae?
你为什么去他家?
Why did you go to his home?
我进出那里的时候肯定被摄像头拍到了。
I must've been caught on camera going in or out of there.
当我在自助餐厅遇到那位奶奶时，
When I met that grandma in the cafeteria,
她说他往孩子头上倒了些东西。
she said he poured something on the child's head.
我没多想，也没在意，
I didn't think much of it and ignored it,
但它一直困扰着我。
but it kept nagging at me.
所以我偷偷溜进了他家。
So I sneaked into his home.
我知道这样不对，但我还是离开了，因为我什么都没找到。
I knew it was wrong, but I just left because I didn't find anything.
我会为杀人付出代价…
I'll pay for killing...
康duke energy秀
Kang Duk Soo
我是想说的，但是…
I was going to, but...
除非我抓到杀奇库克的凶手。
not until I catch Chi Kook's killer.
请给我截止时间。
Please give me until then.
好吗?
Please?
你怎么解释?
How can you explain that?
那个用卡车挡住我的奥兹人
The OZ guy who blocked me with his truck...
当时我正要去救奉仪
when I was on my way to save Bong Yi.
跟踪你的那个人。
The guy who was tailing you.
我不知道。我也快疯了。
I don't know. That's driving me crazy too.
我不知道他们是谁。
I don't know who they are.
这是怎么呢他在骗我吗?
What's going on? Is he lying to me?
还是真的有人……
Or is there really someone...
谁想把他的罪行揽到自己头上?
who's trying to take credit for his crimes?
你说我帮他收拾是什么意思?
What do you mean I cleaned up after him?
正确的。看起来他确实不知道李警探的事。
Right. It did seem like he had no idea about Detective Lee.
请。
Please.
直到我抓到杀害奇果的凶手。
Just until I catch those who killed Chi Kook.
给我时间。
Give me until then.
一旦找到，我就去自首。
Once I do, I'll turn myself in.
求你了，我求求你了。
Please, I'm begging you.
侦探柯,
Detective Ko,
我知道我现在厚颜无耻，两面派。
I know I'm being brazen and two-faced.
但再给我一点时间。
But give me a little more time.
一旦我抓到他们，
Once I catch them,
我会受到无尽的惩罚。
I'll receive my endless punishment.
我还得检查一下。
I should still check.
官荣格?
Officer Jung?
是的，我打电话问他释放的时间。
Yes, I called to ask him about the time of release.
你为什么这么问?
Why do you ask?
什么?嗯…
What? Well...
还有什么?你还跟他说了什么?
What else? What else did you tell him?
Suseong系列谋杀案背后真正的罪犯…
That the real culprit behind the Suseong serial murders...
可能是李在植。
could be Lee Jae Shik.
李的DNA被发现了
And that Lee's DNA was found...
用来杀死姜德洙的武器
on the weapon used to kill Kang Duk Soo,
这可能会让他成为下一个目标。
which could make him the next target.
你应该来找我，而不是他。
You should've come to me, not him.
那你就会想杀了他。
Then you would've tried to kill him.
总之，我得出城去工作了。
Anyway, I need to head out of the city for work.
这倒提醒了我。
That reminds me.
奉仪带了礼物给恩昌。
Bong Yi came by with a present for Eun Chong.
我明白了。
I see.
她为说孩子的坏话而感到内疚。
She feels bad for badmouthing the baby.
她的愤怒压倒了她。
Her anger got the best of her.
我明白了。
I understand.
她的陈述和荣格警官的一致。
Her statement coincides with Officer Jung's.
真的会有模仿者吗?
Could there really be a copycat?
(“夏洛克宏炬”)
("Sherlock Hong Ju")
等待。我的宝贝。我的宝贝…
Wait. My baby. My baby...
-我的宝贝会…——移动!
- My baby will... - Move!
别这么苛刻。让我扶你起来。
Don't be so harsh. Let me help you up.
-你没事吧?-带我去见我的孩子。
- Are you all right? - Take me to my baby.
——我的宝贝。-你的孩子呢，夫人?
- My baby. - Where is your baby, ma'am?
在那里。她的
Over there. Her.
崔香港居吗?你是崔女士的母亲吗?
Choi Hong Ju? Are you Ms. Choi's mother?
是的。
Yes.
我们有她的联系电话，对吧?
We have her contact number, don't we?
给她打个电话，护送她妈妈去见她。
Give her a call and escort her mother to her.
这个年轻人……
This young man...
我会给你女儿打电话，带你去见她。
will call your daughter and take you to her.
-确保他们见面。——是的,先生。
- Make sure they meet. - Yes, sir.
好吧,。
All right, then.
——走吧。——我的宝贝。
- Let's go. - My baby.
我的女孩。
My girl.
邦伊知道吗?
Does Bong Yi know?
所以我们分手了。
That's why we broke up.
她说她不介意
She says she's fine with it,
但我无法忍受那种负罪感。
but I couldn't bear the guilt.
就是这个地方。
This is the place.
你是来见谁的?
Whom are you here to meet?
我是来护送崔洪柱女士的母亲的。
I'm here escorting Ms. Choi Hong Ju's mother.
崔女士的母亲?
Ms. Choi's mother?
你认识她吗?
Do you know her?
一个男人和崔女士的母亲在一起。
A man is here with Ms. Choi's mother.
——她的母亲吗?——是的。
- Her mother? - Yes.
她肯定说过她是个孤儿。
I'm sure she said she's an orphan.
只是一个第二。
Just a second.
您所联系的人无法接听。
The person you have reached is unavailable.
-那边的你。——什么?
- You over there. - What?
你以为你在干什么?
What do you think you're doing?
这只是我的个人社交媒体账户。
This is only for my personal social media account.
-马上删掉!-我的宝贝。
- Delete that right now! - My sweet baby.
你太吵了，女士。
You sure are loud, lady.
不,不喜欢。放开我。
No, don't. Let go of me.
不!
No!
我会把你的脸弄模糊的。
I'll make sure your face is blurred out.
崔女士不接电话，所以在她接之前
Ms. Choi isn't picking up, so until she does...
-她去哪儿了?——对不起?
- Where did she go? - Sorry?
她去哪儿了?
Where did she go?
但她就在这里。
But she was right here.
恩昌去了哪里?
Where did Eun Chong go?
恩庄吗?
Eun Chong?
荣格警官为什么甩了你?
Why did Officer Jung dump you?
嗯,你知道的。
Well, you know.
反正我们也不是真的约会过。
It's not like we actually dated anyway.
他受够了我。现在快乐吗?
He got fed up with me. Happy now?
我明白了。
I see.
不管怎样，你为什么要用Ba Reum…
Anyway, why did you punch Ba Reum...
今天早些时候吗?
earlier today?
我错怪了他。
I wrongfully accused him...
并为此道歉。
and apologized for it.
锣易建联。
Bong Yi.
幸福,好吗?
Be happy, okay?
如果你继续痛苦和心碎，
If you stay miserable and heartbroken,
你祖母会很伤心的。
your grandmother will be in sorrow.
也要保持坚强。
Stay strong as well.
顺便问一下，你之前为什么来车站?
By the way, why were you at the station earlier?
你也给我打过几次电话。
You had called me a few times too.
那天救了我的年轻学生。
The young student who saved me that day.
穿校服的那个。
The one with the school uniform.
我发现他。
I found him.
——真的吗?,但是……
- Really? - But...
是宋佑翰。
it was Sung Yo Han.
什么?
What?
我自己证实了。
I confirmed it myself.
这就是宋佑翰。
It was Sung Yo Han.
你不觉得奇怪吗?
Doesn't it seem odd to you?
精神病患者是众所周知的演员。
You know, psychopaths are known actors.
他装模作样，让自己看起来像个天真的孩子。
He put on a show to look like an innocent boy.
-那是演戏。——没有。
- It was an act. - No.
他不是假装。
He wasn't pretending.
他真的很担心。
He was genuinely worried.
当他背着我的时候，
When he carried me on his back,
我是无意识的。
I was unconscious.
然而，有那么几秒钟，我短暂地意识到了。
However, for a few seconds, I was briefly conscious.
就在那时，我听到了他绝望的话语。
And that's when I heard his desperate words.
想想如果你死了，你的家人会有多难过。
Think about how sad your family will be if you die.
你的爸爸妈妈。
Your mom and dad.
奶奶。
Grandma.
他为什么要假装…
Why would he put on an act...
对于一个昏迷的人来说?
for someone who was unconscious?
他显然是发自内心的。
He was obviously speaking from the heart.
但精神变态者会这样吗?
But can a psychopath be like that?
你觉得这说得通吗?
Does this make any sense to you?
如果……
What if...
我是说，如果…
And I mean, what if...
如果Sung Yo Han不是凶手呢?
What if Sung Yo Han wasn't the killer?
我的奶奶……
My grandma...
和父亲Ko。
and Father Ko.
也就是说有人杀了他们俩。
It means someone else killed them both.
你是荒谬的。
You're being ridiculous.
是Sung Yo Han杀了我弟弟。
It was Sung Yo Han who killed my brother.
但是…
But...
(Moojin警察机构)
(Moojin Police Agency)
大家肯定都打卡下班了。
Everyone must've already clocked out.
他们的队长随时可能因为压力而秃顶，
Their captain might go bald from the stress any day now,
但他们似乎有很多空闲时间。
but they seem to have a lot of time on their hands.
我还是不知道该不该相信高木奇。
I still don't know whether to believe Ko Moo Chi or not.
(食肉动物系列谋杀案)
(Predator Serial Murder Case)
为什么这个在申警探的桌子上?
Why is this at Detective Shin's desk?
(圣母爱之家)
(Holy Mother House of Love)
(捐赠2000美元)
(Donation, 2,000 dollars)
"圣母爱之家"?
"Holy Mother House of Love"?
那不是……
Isn't that...
不。他不是我的兄弟。
No. He is not my brother.
他不遵守诺言。
He does not keep promises.
“麦克拉”?
"Michaela"?
宋秀镐从古陵回来后哭了一整夜……
Song Soo Ho wept all night when he got back from Guryeong...
就在那个时候，男孩的家人被谋杀了。
and it was around the time the boy's family was murdered.
不可能。
No way.
我们是警察。你没报告过有人失踪吗?
This is the police. Didn't you report a missing person?
是的。
Yes.
你能检查一下我刚发给你的照片吗?
Could you check the photo I just sent you?
是的，她是我妻子。
Yes, she's my wife.
我在哪儿见你?
Where can I meet you?
我们自己送她回家，这样我们就不会想念彼此了。
We'll take her home ourselves so we don't miss each other.
请在家里等我们。
Please wait for us at home.
(Yongdong区)
(The Yongdong Precinct)
如果Sung Yo Han不是凶手呢?
What if Sung Yo Han wasn't the killer?
我奶奶和柯神父。
My grandma and Father Ko.
也就是说有人杀了他们俩。
It means someone else killed them both.
谢谢你！再见。
Thank you. Goodbye.
亲爱的，你把孩子带哪去了?
Honey, where did you bring the baby?
他是我们的孩子。他是我们的。
He's our baby. He's ours.
——亲爱的!-他是我们的孩子。
- Honey! - He's our baby.
喂?
Hello?
你在哪里找到我妻子的?
Where did you find my wife?
蜂蜜。
Honey.
我听说他们在附近找到了你。
I heard they found you somewhere near here.
你还记得你是在哪里捡到这个宝贝的吗?
Do you remember where you picked up this baby?
这是谁的孩子?快点告诉我。
Whose baby is this? Hurry up and tell me.
孩子的妈妈一定在找孩子。我们会有麻烦的。
The baby's mother must be looking for the baby. We'll be in trouble.
他是我们的孩子。他是我们的。
He's our baby. He's ours.
你知道吗?我们带他去附近的警局吧。
You know what? Let's just take him to the nearby precinct station.
——不!——亲爱的!亲爱的!
- No! - Honey! Honey!
蜂蜜……
Honey...
亲爱的!
Honey!
亲爱的!亲爱的!
Honey! Honey!
恩庄!恩庄!
Eun Chong! Eun Chong!
发生事故了吗?
Was there an accident?
是的。
Yes.
它看起来很严重。
It looks serious.
——看。——我的天哪。
- Look. - My goodness.
-你不能去。——宝贝!的宝贝!等等!
- You can't go. - The baby! The baby! Wait!
的宝贝!等等!的宝贝!
The baby! Wait! The baby!
天啊，在这儿。
Gosh, here it is.
他什么时候拍的?
When did he take this?
人们认为证据管理团队是某种小吃店。
People think the evidence managing team is some kind of a snack bar.
他们只是来拿东西。
They just come and take things.
所有这些证据都证明成友韩是罪魁祸首。
All this evidence proves that Sung Yo Han was the culprit.
我会一一过目，证明……
I'll go through every single one and prove...
肯定是他。
that it was definitely him.
(“什么是精神病患者?”)
("What is a Psychopath?")
“莫津监狱接收一名患有艾滋病的囚犯。”
"Moojin Prison accepts an inmate with AIDS."
"所有囚犯都要接受血液测试"
"All inmates receive blood tests."
这是什么来着?
What was this again?
这是什么?
What's this?
(当地急救医疗中心)
(Local Emergency Medical Center)
怎么样?
How did it go?
幸运的是，孩子没事。他只是有点震惊。
Fortunately, the baby is okay. He was just a little shocked.
幸运的是，他甚至没有任何瘀伤。
Luckily, he didn't even get any bruises either.
那我妻子怎么样?
Then how's my wife?
她受伤更多是因为她想保护孩子。
She got hurt more because she was trying to protect the baby.
过了今晚我们就知道她能不能活下来了。
We'll know if she'll make it or not after tonight.
(当地急救医疗中心)
(Local Emergency Medical Center)
嘿,色情的家伙。
Hey, Porn Dude.
你看到少了什么了吗?
Do you see what's missing?
我想让你弄清楚。
I want you to figure it out.
天啊，剩下的太少了。我不知道是否有可能。
Gosh, there's too little of it left. I don't know if it'll be possible.
只是说“好。”
Just say "Okay."
好吧。我得到了它。
Okay. I got it.
我会试一试，但要花些时间。
I'll give it a try, but it'll take some time.
我会试着查出这是谁的孩子。
I'll try to find out whose baby this is.
今晚请照顾他。
Please take care of him for tonight.
打扰一下!我的宝宝在哪里?你知道我的孩子在哪儿吗?
Excuse me! Where's my baby? Do you know where my baby is?
这个婴儿在这条路上发生了事故。
The baby was involved in the accident down the road.
只是一个第二。让我帮您查一下。
Just a second. Let me check for you.
是Sung Yo Han的孩子?
It was Sung Yo Han's baby?
我的宝宝在哪里?
Where's my baby?
韩秀俊最终伤害了我的整个家庭。
Han Seo Joon ended up hurting my entire family.
他已经杀了玄秀和玄硕。
He already killed Hyun Soo and Hyun Suk.
现在轮到我妻子了?
And now my wife?
我的孩子还好吗?
Is my baby okay?
恩昌还好吗?
Is Eun Chong okay?
去告诉你丈夫…
Go and tell your husband...
他最好告诉我他把玄秀埋在哪了…
that he'd better tell me where he buried Hyun Soo...
如果他想救他的孙子。
if he wants to save his grandchild.
如果他不同意，我就杀了他的孙子。
If he doesn't, I'll kill his grandchild.
告诉他我会杀了他的孩子。
Tell him I'll just kill the baby.
请。请……
Please. Please...
请不要伤害孩子。
Please don't hurt the baby.
婴儿做错了什么?
What did the baby do wrong?
那我的孩子们做错了什么?
Then what did my children do wrong?
我想找到玄秀的遗体……
I want to find Hyun Soo's remains...
在我妻子去世之前。
before my wife dies.
所以告诉韩秀俊…
So tell Han Seo Joon...
我有他的孙子…
that I have his grandson...
他最好给我我想要的。
and that he'd better give me what I want.
不…不。
No... No.
嘿,崔女士。
Hey, Ms. Choi.
你给我打了好几次电话。有什么问题吗?
You called me several times. Is there something wrong?
不,没有什么是错的。
No, nothing's wrong.
恩昌在做什么?他睡着了吗?
What's Eun Chong doing? Is he asleep?
是的,他的睡眠。
Yes, he's sleeping.
再见。
Bye.
他就在这里。
There he is.
检察官尹。
Prosecutor Yoon.
你是拒绝逮捕令的检察官
You're the prosecutor who rejected the arrest warrant...
和亨哲，对吗?
on Woo Hyung Chul, right?
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我无话可说。
I have nothing to say.
侦探Ko。
Detective Ko.
醒来。
Wake up.
快点。看看这个。
Hurry. Look at this.
(人类基因测试实验室)
(Human Genetic Testing Laboratory)
这是什么?
What is this?
宋秀镐先生给这里捐了十多年的钱。
Mr. Song Soo Ho donated money to this place for over 10 years.
他还为米凯拉捐了钱。
And he also made separate donations for Michaela.
他也去看她了吗?
Did he also visit her?
他有时来，远远地看着她。
He sometimes came and watched her from afar.
我还记得他的眼神。
I still remember the look in his eyes.
充满了痛苦和悔恨。
It was full of pain and remorse.
这就是他看米凯拉的眼神。
That's how he looked at Michaela.
宋秀镐从古陵回来后哭了一整夜，
Song Soo Ho wept all night when he got back from Guryeong,
就在那个时候，男孩的家人被谋杀了。
and it was around the time the boy's family was murdered.
死的!死的!
Die! Die!
孩子们,我回来了!
Kids, I'm home!
我们有麻烦了。
We have a problem.
孩子的妈妈想杀了孩子，
The child's mom tried to kill the child,
所以我想阻止她
so I was trying to stop her...
在勋的父亲……
And Jae Hoon's father...
是的，在勋很安全。
Yes, Jae Hoon is safe.
我明白了。
I understand.
我不知道里面还有个孩子。
I didn't know there was a child inside.
我不知道房子里还有个孩子。
I didn't know there was a child in the house.
我为什么要杀你的家人?
Why did I kill your family?
因为你妈妈想杀了你。
Because your mom tried to kill you.
因为如果你死了
Because if you died,
我梦想的世界永远不会实现。
the world I dreamt of could never come true.
一个没有像我妹妹这样的受害者的世界。
A world without victims like my sister.
Sung Yo Han为什么来这里?
Why did Sung Yo Han come here?
Jae昭熙。
Jae Hee.
是我，在勋。Jae胡恩。
It's me, Jae Hoon. Jae Hoon.
你还记得我吗?
Do you remember me?
Jae胡恩吗?
Jae Hoon?
Jae胡恩。
Jae Hoon.
是的。
Yes.
发生了什么事?
What happened?
在民，在民。
Jae Min. Jae Min.
不。不。
No. No.
不要去。
Don't go.
不要看。不要发出声音。
Don't look. Don't make a sound.
什么?你什么意思?
What? What do you mean?
不要看，在熙。
Don't look, Jae Hee.
不要发出声音。
Don't make a sound.
什么?
What?
快点。
Hurry up.
这就是为什么Jae Min…
That's why Jae Min...
这就是为什么他……
That's why he...
“我很害怕。我孤独了。”
"I'm scared. I'm lonely."
“我想哭。”
"I want to cry."
“我想得到安慰。但是这里一个人也没有。”
"I want to be comforted. But there's no one here."
“没有人在我身边。”
"No one is by my side."
“我很害怕，在熙。”
"I'm scared, Jae Hee."
Jae昭熙。你什么意思?
Jae Hee. What do you mean?
谁说的?
Who said that?
(人类基因测试实验室)
(Human Genetic Testing Laboratory)
这是怎么呢
What's going on?
我们听到那个不幸的消息后不久，他就来了。
He came not long after we heard the sad news...
恩人。
about the benefactor.
他是两次。
He came twice.
他第二次看上去筋疲力尽。
He looked very exhausted the second time.
他说他那天想和米凯拉单独谈谈，
He said he wanted to talk alone with Michaela that day,
所以我带他们去了那里。
so I took them there.
我想他以为她只是病了。
I think he thought she was just sick.
我想他不知道她是特别的。
I don't think he knew that she was special...
她记得每一个字和每一个动作。
and that she remembered every word and movement.
在这里。
Here.
你一定有很多话要跟她说。
You must have so much to talk about with her...
自从15年后你找到了你妹妹。
since you found your sister after 15 years.
你为什么不和她一起吃点零食呢?
Why don't you share a snack with her?
谢谢你！
Thank you.
Jae昭熙。
Jae Hee.
“Jae昭熙。”
"Jae Hee."
“我很害怕。我孤独了。”
"I'm scared. I'm lonely."
我想哭。
I want to cry.
我想要得到安慰。
I want to be comforted.
但是这里一个人也没有。没有人在我身边。
But there's no one here. No one is by my side.
我很害怕。
I'm scared.
我很害怕，在熙。
I'm scared, Jae Hee.
Sung Yo Han哭了?
Sung Yo Han cried?
还有什么?他还说了什么?
What else? What else did he say?
Jae胡恩。Jae胡恩。
Jae Hoon. Jae Hoon.
Jae胡恩吗?
Jae Hoon?
他提到了我?
He talked about me?
——这就是他。——多么可怕。
- That's him. - How scary.
“大家都怕他，躲着他。”
"Everyone feared him and avoided him."
-别这样，董koo。——下车!
- Stop that, Dong Koo. - Get off!
“在那短暂的一刻，”
"In that brief moment,"
“我看到了那个男孩15年前的眼神。”
"I saw that boy's eyes from 15 years ago."
这是一次突然袭击。
It was a surprise attack.
他会本能地举手辩护。
He would've instinctively raised his hands in defense.
他的手指上有防卫伤。
The defense wounds are on his fingers.
也就是说他还没来得及举手就被袭击了。
That means he was attacked before he could raise his hands.
如果是在他举手之前，
If it was before he could raise his hands,
是一个跟他很亲近的人。
it was someone very close to him.
嗯…是一个追随韩秀俊的囚犯。
Well... It was one of the inmates who follow Han Seo Joon.
他承认他这么做是为了给奇果一个教训……
He confessed that he did it to teach Chi Kook a lesson...
不尊重猎头
for disrespecting the Head Hunter.
和他最亲近的人。
Someone closest to him.
到底是那个男孩吗?
Was it that boy after all?
我想和你谈谈最近的谋杀案。
I'd like to talk to you regarding the recent murders.
这跟我有什么关系?
What does that have to do with me?
我知道是谁干的。
I know who did it.
他是非常危险的。
He's very dangerous.
我想知道……
I wanted to find out...
如果真的是那个男孩。
if it really was that boy.
如果他哭的时候不是在演戏呢?
What if he wasn't acting when he cried...
拥抱红菊的时候?
while hugging Hong Ju?
如果是真心的呢?
What if it was sincere?
你在想什么，妈妈?
What are you thinking about, Mom?
你看起来总是很悲伤，无论你什么时候……
You always look sad whenever you look...
在阳光下。
at the sunlight.
正因为如此，
And because of that,
每当我看到阳光，我也会难过。
I'm sad whenever I see the sunlight too.
无稽之谈。
Nonsense.
我一点也不难过。
I'm not sad at all.
有你在身边，我为什么要生气?
Why would I be when I have you beside me?
4440号囚犯的访客。
The visitor for Inmate 4440.
他拒绝见你。
He refused to see you.
只是我真的必须和他谈谈。
It's just that I really must talk to him.
请再问他一次。
Please ask him once more.
犯人拒绝探访我们也无能为力。
There's nothing we can do when an inmate rejects the visitor.
——请。请再问他一遍。——我很抱歉。
- Please. Please ask him again. - I'm sorry.
然后……
Then...
告诉他是关于他儿子，韩友。
Tell him that it's about his son, Yo Han.
“我简直不敢相信……”
"I couldn't believe..."
"丹尼尔·李告诉我的"
"what Daniel Lee told me,"
“所以我问Joon Sung谁在那里工作……”
"so I asked Joon Sung who worked there..."
我让他去调查财务三队。
I asked him to look into Finance Team Three.
——为什么?-去检查一些东西。
- What for? - To check something.
我需要确认这是否属实。
I need to confirm if it's true.
财务团队三个?
Finance Team Three?
有三队吗?
Is there a team three?
是这个部门的吗?
Is it under this department?
(财务部)
(Finance Department)
我会深入调查的。你知道我的黑客技术。
I'll look deeper into it. You know my hacking skills.
这就是为什么金俊成…
That's why Kim Joon Sung...
Yo Han，我是Joon Sung。
Yo Han, it's Joon Sung.
那个声音信息。
That voice message.
你让我调查的事让我很害怕。
What you asked me to look into has me terrified.
也许黑客不是个好主意。
Maybe hacking wasn't the right idea.
这个组织被称为“OZ”。
The organization goes by the name "OZ".
(1995年1月，科目A:宋佑翰)
(January 1995, Subject A: Sung Yo Han)
(B)报告
(Report on B)
(1995年1月，受试者B:朴在勋)
(January 1995, Subject B: Park Jae Hoon)
李医生说的是实话。
Dr. Lee was telling the truth.
这是令人作呕。
This is sickening.
如何……
How...
怎么会有人做这些事?
How could someone do all this?
凶手是个精神病患者。
The killer is a psychopath.
他没有道德准则。
He doesn't have a moral compass.
现在该做什么?
What now?
我得等等……
I'll have to wait...
直到他恢复知觉。
until he regains consciousness.
为什么不把这一切都报道出来?
Why not just report this whole thing?
我怎么能相信警察呢?
How can I trust the cops?
如果我们利用媒体公开呢?
What if we use the media to go public?
我们面对的是一个秘密行动。
We're up against a black operation.
说出来会害死我们的
Running our mouths about it could lead us to our deaths.
我们无法知道这个程序有多深入。
There's no way to know how deep this program runs.
那我们该怎么办呢?
What can we do then?
我们等李医生醒了再说。
Let's wait until Dr. Lee awakes.
我很害怕。
I'm scared.
韩哟
Yo Han,
如果他们发现我黑了系统怎么办?
what if they find out that I hacked into the system?
暂时离开这个国家。
Leave the country for the time being.
-你呢?-一旦李医生醒来
- What about you? - Once Dr. Lee wakes up,
我们将一起操作。
we'll operate together.
别担心。他马上就起来。
Don't worry. He'll be up soon.
如果她向警方告发我，她就有危险了。
If she reports me to the police, it'll put her in danger.
我确定她就是在这里下车的。
I'm sure this is where she got off.
Gudong吗?
Gudong?
那是容巴留姆居住的地方。
It's where Jung Ba Reum lives.
如果她告诉他了呢?容巴容不能知道。
What if she tells him? Jung Ba Reum must not know.
要是那晚我没穿俊成的夹克就好了。
If only I hadn't worn Joon Sung's jacket that night.
他是我唯一的朋友。
He had been my only friend.
其他人指责我是亨特猎头的儿子，
Others pointed their fingers at me for being Head Hunter's son,
但俊成总是站在我这边。
but Joon Sung always took my side.
但因为我…
But because of me...
我要亲手杀了容巴容。
I'll kill Jung Ba Reum myself.
所以他在他家放了我的照片。
That's why he had photos of me at his house.
为什么宋友韩把巴留的照片挂在墙上?
Why did Sung Yo Han have Ba Reum's photos on his wall?
我们刚拿到搜查令。
We just got a search warrant.
搜查令?
A search warrant?
李医生，你没事吧?
Dr. Lee, are you all right?
如果韩果那天不在车里…
If Han Kook wasn't in his car that day...
我们在他车里发现了谁的血迹?
Whose blood did we find in his car?
会是谁呢?
Who could it have been?
(人类基因测试实验室)
(Human Genetic Testing Laboratory)
Jae昭熙。
Jae Hee.
我们是唯一的…
We're the only ones...
留在这个世界上。
left in this world now.
什么?
What?
我越想越觉得
The more I think about it,
我就更确定那不是Sung Yo Han。
the more I'm sure it's not Sung Yo Han.
但没办法证实我的怀疑。
But there's no way to confirm my suspicions.
该死的,这很伤我的心。
Darn, that hurts.
这是正确的。我割破了他的胳膊。
That's right. I slit his arm.
只有腹部中枪。
Nothing other than a gunshot to the abdomen.
他左臂上一定有个伤疤。
He must have a scar on his left arm.
刀伤被刀刺伤的人对这里。
One inflicted by a knife. Right about here.
他胳膊上什么都没有。
There's nothing on his arm.
——真的吗?你确定吗?-你自己看吧。
- Really? Are you sure? - See for yourself.
什么都有。
Nothing's there.
那为什么Sung Yo Han是嫌疑人?
Then why was Sung Yo Han a suspect?
我清楚地告诉过你发生了什么。
I clearly told you what happened.
你在说什么?看。
What are you talking about? Look.
你的口供里没有。
It's not in the statement you gave.
什么?这是奇怪的。
What? That's odd.
我说得很清楚。
I clearly said it.
等待。
Wait.
我想我的刀割破了他的胳膊。
I think I cut his arm with my knife.
——你做了吗?——左侧。
- You did? - Left side.
我觉得是他的左臂。
I think it was his left arm.
好吧。我会告诉康警探的。
Okay. I'll tell Detective Kang.
你跟谁说的?你确定吗?
Who did you tell this? Are you sure?
那么是谁没有上报呢?
Who failed to report it then?
你确定你割伤了袭击者的手臂吗?
Are you sure you cut your attacker's arm?
哦,好吧…
Oh, well...
我想我错了。
I guess I was mistaken.
我检查了几件东西后再打给你。
I'll get back to you after I check a few things.
好吧。
Okay.
他忘记转达口信了吗?
Did he forget to relay the message?
真不敢相信巴勒姆竟然忘了告诉他这么重要的证据。
I can't believe Ba Reum forgot to tell him such important evidence.
手机关机了。请留言…
The phone is turned off. Please leave a message...
成友韩来取韩秀俊的血。
Sung Yo Han came to collect Han Seo Joon's blood.
他不是来杀娜奇果的。
He wasn't here to kill Na Chi Kook.
如果不是Sung Yo Han呢?
What if it wasn't Sung Yo Han?
那是谁呢?
Then who could it be?
我们一起把箱子搬到了礼堂。
We carried the box to the auditorium together.
好了。
There we go.
-我们聊天道别。——祝你好运。不要让害怕。
- We chatted and said goodbye. - Good luck. Don't get intimidated.
——好吧,再见。-在我看到奇果离开后
- Okay, bye. - After I saw Chi Kook leave,
我把盒子推了进去。
I pushed the box inside.
凶手是如何移动一个昏迷的成年人的…
How did the killer manage to move a grown, unconscious man...
一直到礼堂里的魔盒吗?
all the way to the magic box in the auditorium?
原谅我。
Excuse me.
犯人4440刚刚同意见你。
Inmate 4440 just agreed to meet you.
英航Reum。
Ba Reum.
巴·雷姆，我有事要问你。
Ba Reum, I have something to ask.
他看起来很疲惫。
He looks so exhausted.
如果魔盒就在这里呢?
What if the magic box was here?
如果这就是凶手把尸体放进去的地方呢?
What if this was where the killer put the body inside?
在盒子里面，有一面斜着放的镜子。
Inside the box, there's a mirror placed diagonally.
你让那个人走进镜子里。
You make the person go inside the mirror.
我把它带进来的时候就落在这里了……
I left it here once I brought it in...
这样就不会妨碍别人了。
so it wouldn't get in people's ways.
我离开去吃午饭了。
I stepped away for lunch.
我只知道巴·雷姆告诉我的。
I only know what Ba Reum told me.
如果他骗了我怎么办?
What if he lied to me?
但他为什么要撒谎?
But why would he lie?
他没有理由撒谎。
He has no reason to lie.
如果是巴雷姆呢?
What if it was Ba Reum?
(老鼠)
(Mouse)
他辞职了吗?通过电子邮件吗?
He quit? Via email?
每一秒都追踪巴留姆的下落。
Trace Ba Reum's whereabouts down to every second.
官荣格?
Officer Jung?
我会用最残忍的方式杀了你。
I'll kill you using the worst way possible.
你只是等待。
You just wait.
会比你想象的要多。
It'll be more than what you can imagine.
英航Reum !
Ba Reum!
你去报警了吗?
By any chance, did you go to the police?
我要你追踪这个人。
I want you to trace this person.
我会让一切恢复正常。
I'll put everything back to normal.
金俊成说他黑了财务三队的系统。
Kim Joon Sung said he hacked Finance Team Three's system.
我不会让你死的。
I'm not going to let you die.
先生，我真的想吃鸡肉。
Sir, I really want to eat chicken.
天啊，算了吧。
My gosh, forget it.
(《我的室友是Gumiho》将于5月26日晚10:30首播。)
("My Roommate is a Gumiho" first airs on May 26 at 10:30pm.)